(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-04T23:15:02.563262",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あ、あ、ああ、皆様ー！
Ah, ah, ah, everyone!
うおー！
Whoooo!
いいね、コメント元気だね。
Nice, the chat is so energetic!
本日は、風真いろは生誕ライブ 2026「Wind Trails」にご来場いただきまして、
Thank you so much for coming to Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026 "Wind Trails" today!
誠に、ありがとうございます！
Thank you very, very much!
いぇーい！
Yay!
開演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Before the show begins, I have a few requests and announcements for everyone.
開演中、カメラやスマートフォンなどは、
During the show, for cameras and smartphones...
えー、電源切られると見れなくなって困るので、電源は切らず、写真撮影などね、大量にしていただき、
if they're turned off you won't be able to watch, so keep them on and take tons of photos,
当配信のハッシュタグ「#風真いろは生誕ライブ2026」で、
and using this stream's hashtag #風真いろは生誕ライブ2026,
SNSに大量に画像をポストしてください！
please post lots and lots of pictures on social media!
目指せ、Xトレンド1位！よろしくお願いしまーす！
Let's aim for the #1 trend on X! I'm counting on you!
あ、あの、でもスマホね、いっぱい写真撮ったりすると、充電なくなっちゃいそうなんで、
Ah, but if you take tons of photos on your phone, you might run out of battery,
スマホで見ている勢は、充電しっかりしてくださいねー！
so to everyone watching on a smartphone, please make sure it's fully charged!
はい！そしてその2！
All right! Next, rule number two!
激しく頭を振る、
Violent headbanging,
えー、激しくペンライトを振るなどはですね、あの、あなた様のご自宅を破壊する危険性がございますので、
or swinging penlights violently carries the risk of destroying your home,
あの、破壊されてもですね、こちらは責任一切負えませんので、
so even if something breaks, we cannot take any responsibility for it,
あのお気をつけくださーい！ダメだよ、みんな！
so please be careful! Don't do it, okay, everyone?
あ、そしてあと、もう1個、その3！
Ah, and one more thing, rule number three!
あの、今からハヤシライスを準備しようとしてる奴は間に合わないからやめな！絶対間に合わないから！
Anyone trying to make hashed beef rice right now, you won't make it in time, so stop! You definitely won't make it in time!
まあね、何か食べたり飲んだりしながら、ぜひね、ゆっくり楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！
Well, I hope you'll relax and enjoy the show while having something to eat or drink!
それでは、もうそろそろ始まるので、
With that said, we'll be starting very soon,
今しばらくお待ちください。
so please wait just a little longer.
最後まで見てねー！
Watch until the very end, okay?!
風真いろは 生誕ライブ 2026
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026!
行くよー！
Here we go!
いっせーので鳴り響いた スタートの合図
Ready, set, go! The starting signal rang out,
なぞった線で結んだ世界
connecting a world traced by lines,
色付けていく ここから
which we'll start coloring in right from here.
物心がつく頃 すでに此処にあった
By the time I was old enough to know, it was already here;
僕じゃない誰かの記憶は
the memories of someone who wasn't me
夕陽とともに蘇る
come flooding back with the setting sun.
古ぼけた絵本を取り出して
Pulling out a faded picture book,
落書きの中に1つの答えを見つけた
I found a single answer hidden among the doodles.
自分の価値に目を疑って どこまでだって堕ちていけるの
Doubting my own worth, wondering how far I could fall,
どこか遠くに消えてしまいたい こんな世界じゃ僕はいらない
I wanted to disappear far away; there's no place for me in a world like this.
カウントダウンは始まっているよ
The countdown has already begun.
いっせーので声を上げて 聴こえてくるんだ
On the count of three, we raise our voices, and it echoes back to me.
自分の影の長さに気付く もうこんな時間だ
Noticing the length of my shadow, I realize how late it's gotten.
一等星が顔を出した 届きそうで手を伸ばした
The first star peeked out; feeling like I could reach it, I stretched out my hand.
「次は僕に着いてきなよ」と どんな暗闇でも
"Follow me next time," through any darkness.
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet!
幕は上がりだした
The curtain has started to rise.
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet!
色付けていく ここから
We'll start coloring it in right from here.
10年後の僕らは すれ違いばかりで
Ten years later, we keep passing each other by,
幻想に想いを馳せては “戻れない”そう思い込んだ
and lost in illusions, I convinced myself that "there's no going back."
くたびれた心に追い討ちを
Dealing another blow to an exhausted heart,
あの頃と変わらない夕陽も 何とも思わない
even the sunset, unchanged since back then, makes me feel nothing.
自分を信じ歩いていければ どこまでだって昇れるのにな
If only I could believe in myself and keep walking, I could climb anywhere,
カットを跨ぐその空白に 大切なモノ見落としている
yet in the blank spaces between cuts, I'm overlooking what's truly precious.
見つけられないと泣きわめく君へ
To you, who cried and shouted, unable to find it...
いっせーので声を上げて 聴こえてくるんだ
On the count of three, we raise our voices, and it echoes back to me.
自分の影の長さに気付く もうこんな時間だ
Noticing the length of my shadow, I realize how late it's gotten.
一等賞で駆け抜ける君 くっついていただけの僕でも
As you sprint past taking first place, even if I was just clinging on behind,
君の前を歩けるかな？
I wonder if I can walk ahead of you?
こんな頼りない僕でも
Even someone as unreliable as me...
宝箱はホコリをかぶったまま
The treasure box was left covered in dust,
無くした鍵はずっと 君のポケットの中にあった
and the lost key had been inside your pocket all along.
散らばっていた全てが 今ひとつに重なる
Everything that was scattered apart now overlaps into one.
手を取り始めよう 僕たちの物語
Let's take hands and begin our story.
一度は いらないと思った
Though I once thought I didn't need it,
今なら胸を張れる 気がしたんだ
I feel like now, I can finally hold my head high.
愛おしくて
So precious and dear...
掛け声はいつも
Our call is always...
いっせーので声を上げて 聴こえてくるんだ
On the count of three, we raise our voices, and it echoes back to me.
自分の影の長さに気付く もうこんな時間だ
Noticing the length of my shadow, I realize how late it's gotten.
一等星が顔を出した 届きそうで手を伸ばした
The first star peeked out; feeling like I could reach it, I stretched out my hand.
「次は僕に着いてきなよ」と どんな暗闇でも
"Follow me next time," through any darkness.
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet!
泣きじゃくった声で
With a weeping voice,
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet!
笑う君が見えた
I saw you smiling.
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet!
幕は上がりだした
The curtain has started to rise.
もういいかい？ もういいよ
Are you ready? Ready now!
色付けていく ここから
We'll start coloring it in right from here.
はい！ということで、
All right! And so...
始まりましたー！
We've officially begun!
風真いろは 生誕LIVE 2024...
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2024...
スタート！みんな、こんばんはー！
...has started! Good evening, everyone!
見てるー？
Are you watching?
はい、ということで本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
All right, today's hashtag is right here!
こちらね、みんな、いっぱいポストしていっぱいカッコいいとこ撮ってくださいね！
Post using this a lot and take lots of cool screenshots, okay?
頼むよ！
I'm counting on you!
この風真いろはがイケメンであることを世の中に知らしめられるのは、
Because the only ones who can show the world how cool Kazama Iroha is...
お前たちだけなので、よろしくお願いします！
...is all of you, so please do your best!
はい、そして今回のライブ、タイトルがついております！
Yes, and this live concert has a title!
『Wind Trails』というタイトルがついておりますが、
It's titled "Wind Trails."
まあ、そのまま訳して結構お気づきの方も多かったんですが、
Many of you probably figured it out from the direct translation,
「風の軌跡」という意味を込めて付けさせていただき、
but I gave it that title with the meaning "Trails of the Wind,"
今回ライブ色々頑張って考えさせていただきました！
and worked hard putting a lot of thought into this live!
なのでね、最後まで楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！
So I hope you'll enjoy it all the way to the end!
そして！1曲目、「かくれんぼ」歌わせていただきましたー！
And for the first song, I performed "Kakurenbo"!
どうだったかなー？
How did you like it?
はい。そして今日、室内ライブだと思ったでしょ？
Yup! And you probably thought today was an indoor concert, right?
見てー！
Look!
曲中にドームが開きましたー！イェーイ！
The dome opened right in the middle of the song! Yay!
すごーい！
Amazing!
やっぱね、なかなか現地ライブってできてもさ、青空の下で歌ってることってないので、
You know, even when we get to do in-person lives, we rarely ever get to sing under a blue sky,
いつか俺たちとお前たちの次元が混ざり合って、空の下で歌えるような世界が来るかもしれないけど、
so while a day when our dimensions blend and we can sing under the sky together might come,
やってみたくてね、今回は空の下で歌うっていう演出をやらせていただきましたー！
I really wanted to try it, so we went with this stage effect of singing under the open sky!
めっちゃいいでしょ？
Pretty awesome, right?
そしてステージもめっちゃかっこいいんで。
And the stage looks super cool, too.
今日はね、多分いっぱい見る機会あると思いますが、
You'll probably have plenty of chances to see it today,
ゆっくり隅から隅まで、アーカイブ勢もね、きっといると思うんで、本当にいろんな細部こだわってるので細かく見てくださいねー！
but take your time looking at every corner! I'm sure people will watch the archive too, so please look closely at all the details!
ということで、お水飲んでいいですかね？
And with that, is it okay if I drink some water?
お水を...お...
Some water...
やめろ！俺の頭をいじっ...やべっ！
Stop it! Don't mess with my head—whoops!
頭をいじくり回されて、
After having my head messed around with,
セットセットになりました。
it's all properly styled now.
そして水が...今日水用意してくれたんだよね。
And as for the water... they prepared some for me today.
みんなに見える水。
Water that everyone can see!
うまっ！
Delicious!
美味すぎる！この...このフリはちょっと怒られそうだからあんまできないけど、
So tasty! I can't really do this dance move too much or I might get scolded,
美味すぎる！
but it's delicious!
美味いな。
So good.
これであと1時間やるか。
Shall we keep going for another hour like this?
そんなわけにもいかないんで、一回ね、水ちょっと返して。
Just kidding, that's not happening, so let me put the water back.
それじゃあ、水分補給もさせてもらって、息も整えたところで、
Well then, now that I've hydrated and caught my breath,
はい、次の曲早速やっていきたいと思います！
let's move right into the next song!
それでは、次の曲聴いてください。
Without further ado, please listen to the next song:
「白線」
"Hakusen."
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line across the clear sky
あの地平を超えて
Crossing beyond that horizon
はい！はい！はい！はい！もっとー！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! More! Hai! Hai!
始まりはちょっと軽い期待で
It started with just a little casual anticipation,
その欠片そっとポケットしまって
and I gently tucked those fragments into my pocket.
屋上 遠い空の向こう見ていた
On the rooftop, I gazed far beyond the distant sky.
この足でどこにいけるかなんて
I didn't know how far these feet could take me,
わかってないけど わかっているんだ
but deep down, I already knew.
白昼 淡い月に 手をのばした
In broad daylight, I reached out my hand toward the pale moon.
かすれたエコー でも答えはもう
Faint echoes, yet the answer was already there,
はじめからちゃんと持っていたんだよ
held firmly within me right from the very start.
メイビー この想いは
Maybe this feeling
マスビー 熱を増して
Must be growing hotter
ほらね、飛べるんだ
See, I really can fly!
もっと高く 高くまで 羽ばたいてみたい
I want to flap my wings and soar higher, even higher!
今日に未来色の 軌道描いて
Drawing a future-colored trajectory across today,
地平の先まで
all the way beyond the horizon!
届かない 歌わない 迷いはいらない！
Won't reach? Won't sing? I don't need those doubts!
どんな世界も 瞬間も 揺るがない アイが在るから
Whatever the world, whatever the moment, because an unwavering love is right here!
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line across the clear sky
不安と期待がアンビバレント
Anxiety and anticipation in ambivalence
でも声は もう気づいてる
But my voice has already noticed
もっと高く 高く 飛んで行ける
I can fly higher and higher!
途切れ途切れの一縷でも
Even if it was just a fragile, broken thread,
紡いでたら「一途」に変わったよ
as I spun it together, it turned into single-minded devotion.
あたりさわりない言葉じゃ
Safe and harmless words alone
覆いきれないほどのマイワールド
aren't enough to cover my world.
明日で呼ぶ声の持ち主は
The one calling out to me from tomorrow
他でもないこの心だった
was none other than my own heart.
言えないでいるその言葉も
Even those words left unspoken
「言葉」だと足りないだけ
are just something mere "words" can't express.
掴んだもの 落としたもの
What I grasped, what I dropped...
転んだって立って見えた視界から
From the view I saw after falling and standing back up,
ロックユー！解き放って
Rock you! Unleash it!
フォーユー！響きだして
For you! Start echoing!
景色変えてゆく
Changing the scenery!
まだ遠く遠くまで広がった空に
Into the sky stretching far, far into the distance,
やっと踏み出すこの一歩なんてちっぽけだけど
this step I'm finally taking might be tiny, but
届かない場所へと続いていく
it continues toward a place beyond reach.
どんな風に雨に消えない白線を描く
I'll draw a white line that won't fade in any wind or rain.
もっと高く高くまで羽ばたいていたい
I want to keep fluttering higher and higher,
そして彼方色で繋ぐリープ 地平で待ってて
and leap connecting to distant colors—wait for me at the horizon!
もう願いに嘘はない ここが好き！
I won't lie about my wishes anymore; I love it here!
どんな世界も瞬間も輝く アイが在るから
Every world and every moment shines, because there is love!
今はただ想うこと言えばいい
Right now, I just need to say what's on my mind:
「愛しているよ！！」
"I love you!!"
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line across the clear sky,
不安と期待とがアンビバレント
anxiety and anticipation feeling ambivalent,
でも「君」はもう気づいてる
but "you" have already realized:
もっと高く高く高く飛んでいける！
We can fly higher, higher, and higher!
もっと
More...
鏡よ教えて 私の証は
Mirror, please tell me, where is the proof of who I am?
どこにあるのだろう 分からない 分からないよ
Where could it be? I don't know, I just don't know.
周りと比べたってさ 虚しくなるだけ
Even if I compare myself to others, it only makes me feel empty.
あぁノイズが海鳴りのように ナミダを奪う
Ah, like the roar of the sea, the noise washes away my tears.
切り取った風景を 道しるべにしよう
Let's turn this captured scene into our guiding light.
そうだ 傷ついた感情も 連れて行くから
That's right, because I'll carry even my hurt feelings along.
そっと響くカンパネラ 新しい未来を感じてる
Softly ringing campanella, I feel a brand new future.
怖くたって進むしかないでしょ？ 遠くまで
Even if it's scary, we have to move forward, right? Far away...
もっと もっと
More, more...
届けこの祈りよ光となれ
Reach out, my prayer—become the light!
もっと もっと
More, more...
少しずつでもいい「私」という答えを
Little by little is fine, finding the answer of "who I am."
もっと
More...
夜空よ教えて 私の証は
Night sky, please tell me, can the proof of who I am
輝けるのかな 見つけたい 見つけたいよ
truly shine? I want to find it, I really want to find it.
誰かの決めたレールは 苦しくなるだけ
Walking tracks laid by someone else only brings pain.
ねぇノイズも力に変えるよ 心に誓う
Hey, I'll turn even the noise into strength—I swear in my heart.
錆びついた運命の 歯車を回そう
Let's turn the rusted gears of fate.
ほら 着飾った感情は 脱ぎ捨てるから
Look, I'll cast away those dressed-up feelings.
そっと紡ぐシンフォニア 叶えたい願いを信じてる
Gently weaving a symphonia, believing in the wishes I want granted.
胸を張って歌うしかないでしょ？ 全力で
We just have to stand tall and sing with all our might, right?
もっと もっと
More, more...
やがて希望の歌に変わる日まで
Until the day it eventually turns into a song of hope!
もっと もっと
More, more...
悩みながらでいい 全てが宝物
It's okay to struggle—everything is a treasure.
いつの日か この声を受け取ってくれたなら
If someday you receive this voice of mine,
この言葉を君に 「もう大丈夫、一人じゃない」
I'll give these words to you: "It's alright now, you're not alone."
強い想いを
These strong feelings...
繋ぐよ 一歩踏み出してみた 優しく世界は微笑む
I'll connect them. I tried taking a step forward, and the world smiled gently.
高鳴る気持ちに身を任せて
Surrendering myself to these racing feelings...
さぁ行こう そっと響くカンパネラ
Let's go! Softly ringing campanella...
新しい未来を感じてる
I can feel a brand-new future.
怖がって進むしかないでしょ
Even if afraid, we've got no choice but to move forward, right?
遠くまで もっと もっと
Farther and farther away, more and more,
届け この祈りよ 光となれ
Reach out, may this prayer turn into light!
もっと もっと
More and more,
少しずつでもいい 私という答えを
Even bit by bit is fine, the answer that is myself...
もっと
More...
誰かが言った いつか空は 灰になって落ちるって
Someone once said that someday, the sky would turn to ash and fall.
妄想の世の中で 日々を喰らっている
Living through the days swallowed up in a world of delusion.
境界線を引いてしまうのも 共感覚のせいにして
Blaming it on synesthesia as I draw boundaries,
街の灯の海で 居場所探している
I'm searching for a place to belong in a sea of city lights.
何処へ行くにも この足は
Wherever I try to go, these feet of mine...
退屈に染まって動かない
are dyed in boredom and won't move.
少しだけ先の景色が 見たいだけなのにな
Even though all I wanted was to see the scenery just a little further ahead.
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったら きっと 頬を濡らしてしまう
If it rains, if it rains, it'll surely wet my cheeks.
枯れてしまった色ですら 愛しくなるのに
Even though even faded colors become so dear to me.
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったら もっと 遠く霞んでしまう
If I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, it'll blur even farther away.
煩くなった雨の音 笑い飛ばしてくれ
Laugh away the sound of the rain that has grown so loud!
誰かが言った いつか溜息は 夜に化けて歌を歌う
Someone once said that someday, sighs will transform into night and sing a song.
妄想の世の中で 日々を喰らっていよう
Devouring the days away in a world of delusion.
優しい嘘をなぞったせいで
Because I traced along gentle lies,
離れる声に気づかない
I didn't notice the voice fading away.
溶けた月が滲ちて 泥に落ちて
The melted moon blurred and fell into the mud,
静かに揺れていた
softly swaying.
夜が降ったら 夜が降ったら きっと 今日を責めてしまう
If night falls, if night falls, I'll surely blame today.
満たされない日々の底で 夢を見ているだけ
At the bottom of unfulfilling days, I'm merely dreaming.
目を逸らしても 目を逸らしても ずっと 後悔と哀の隙間
Even if I look away, even if I look away, always in the gap between regret and sorrow,
取り残されてしまう前に 手を伸ばしてくれ
Before I get left behind, please reach out your hand!
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったら きっと
If it rains, if it rains, surely...
湿るアスファルト背に映して 俯いた
Reflecting the damp asphalt on my back, I looked down,
一人ぼっちで ただ明日に期待をして
All alone, simply holding onto hope for tomorrow.
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったら きっと 頬を濡らしてしまう
If it rains, if it rains, it'll surely wet my cheeks.
枯れてしまった色ですら 愛しくなるのに
Even though even faded colors become so dear to me.
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったら もっと 遠く霞んでしまう
If I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, it'll blur even farther away.
煩くなった雨の音 笑い飛ばしてくれ
Laugh away the sound of the rain that has grown so loud!
繋がっていたいって 信じられる言葉
"I want to stay connected"—words I can believe in,
だってもう 昨日の僕らにおさらば
because we've already said goodbye to who we were yesterday.
青い春を過ごした 遠い稲妻
Our youth spent like distant flashes of lightning,
さっと泣いて 前だけを向けたら
if I could just shed a quick tear and look straight ahead,
きっとどんなに楽になれていたんだろうな
I wonder how much easier things would have been.
この心を揺らした 一筋の望みは
The single ray of hope that made this heart tremble—
ないものねだりはやめた 未完成人間
I've stopped yearning for what I don't have, an imperfect human.
素晴らしき世界だけが
Only this wonderful world
答えを握ってる
holds all the answers.
諦めてしまうほど この先たくさんの
So many regrets lie ahead of you
後悔が君を待ってるけど
that you might feel like giving up, but
もうない 迷いはしないよ
no more; I won't hesitate anymore.
この傷も愛しく 思えてしまうほど
So much that even these wounds feel precious,
重ねてしまうよ 不格好なまんまでいいから
I'll keep piling them on—it's fine to stay clumsy!
走れ その歩幅で
Run at your own pace,
走れ 声轟かせてくれ
run and let your voice roar!
期待と不安を 同じくらい抱きしめて
Embracing hope and anxiety in equal measure,
君と今を紡ぐ未来 照らして
illuminate the future we weave with this present moment!
顔も名前も知らない僕たちが
We, who don't know each other's faces or names,
たった1つの音を掻き鳴らす
strum out a single sound together.
悪戯みたいな 奇跡のような刹那
A fleeting moment like a playful trick, like a miracle.
あっという間に流れる時が
As time flows by in the blink of an eye,
ありのままで在り続ける怖さが
and the fear of continuing to exist just as I am—
失った時間は取り戻せないけれど
We can never regain the time we lost, but
過去を振り返ってばかりじゃ
if you do nothing but dwell on the past...
泣いたっていいんだ
It's okay to cry!
悔しさと痛みだけが
Because only the frustration and pain
君を肯定するから
will validate who you are.
大人になったら 忘れてしまうの
When we grow up, will we forget?
君との約束をした場所は
The place where we made our promise
もうない 覚えていたいよ
is gone now, but I want to remember it.
思い出も愛しく 思えてしまうほど
So much that even the memories feel precious,
重ねてしまうよ 不格好なまんまでいいから
I'll keep piling them on—it's fine to stay clumsy.
その声は どこまでも鳴り響いて
May that voice resound far and wide!
確かな理由を抱いて ここまで来たんだ ああ
Embracing a certain reason, we've come all this way, ah...
まだ終わらない 旅路なんだ
This is a journey that's far from over.
いつしか思いは形になる
Before we know it, our feelings will take shape
この真っ白に染まる朝
on this morning dyed in pure white,
忘れられないまま だから
unable to forget—so...
諦めてしまうほど この先たくさんの
So many things lie ahead that make you want to give up...
もうない 迷いはしないよ
No more; I won't hesitate anymore.
かけがえのないもの 溢れてしまうよ
Irreplaceable treasures overflow,
答えは君のその手の中に
the answer is right inside your hands.
離さないで 物語は一歩前へ
Don't let go; let the story take a step forward!
諦めてしまうほど この先たくさんの
So many regrets lie ahead of you
後悔が君を待ってるけど
that you might feel like giving up, but
もうない 迷いはしないよ
no more; I won't hesitate anymore.
この傷も愛しく 思えてしまうほど
So much that even these wounds feel precious,
重ねてしまうよ 不格好なまんまでいいから
I'll keep piling them on—it's fine to stay clumsy!
走れ その歩幅で
Run at your own pace,
走れ 声轟かせてくれ
run and let your voice roar!
期待と不安を 同じくらい抱きしめて
Embracing hope and anxiety in equal measure,
君と今を紡ぐ未来 照らして
illuminate the future we weave with this present moment!
六兆年と一夜物語
[Title: A Tale of Six Trillion Years and a Night]
名も無い時代の集落の
In a village from an era without a name,
名も無い幼い少年の
about a nameless young boy,
誰も知らない おとぎばなし
a fairy tale that nobody knows.
産まれついた時から
Ever since the moment I was born,
忌み子 鬼の子として
treated as an outcast, as a demon child,
その身に余る 罰を受けた
I received punishments far too harsh for my body.
悲しい事は
Though there is nothing
何も無いけど
that feels sad,
夕焼け小焼け
as the sunset glows,
手を引かれてさ
someone took me by the hand.
知らない 知らない
I don't know, I don't know,
僕は何も知らない
I don't know anything at all.
叱られた後のやさしさも
Not the kindness after being scolded,
雨上がりの手の温もりも
nor the warmth of a hand after the rain.
でも本当は 本当は 本当に寒いんだ
But the truth is, the truth is, I'm really so cold.
死なない 死なない
I don't die, I don't die,
僕はなんで死なない？
why won't I die?
夢のひとつも見れないくせに
Even though I can't even dream a single dream.
誰も知らない おとぎ話は
A fairy tale that nobody knows
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
was swallowed into the sunset and faded away.
吐き出す様な暴力と
Through sickening violence
蔑んだ目の毎日に
and days filled with contemptuous glares,
君はいつしか そこに立ってた
before I knew it, you were standing there.
話しかけちゃだめなのに
Even though you shouldn't talk to me,
「君の名前が知りたいな」
"I want to know your name."
ごめんね 名前も舌も無いんだ
I'm sorry, I have neither a name nor a tongue.
僕の居場所は 何処にも無いのに
Even though I have nowhere I belong,
「一緒に帰ろう」 手を引かれてさ
"Let's go home together," you took my hand.
知らない 知らない
I don't know, I don't know,
僕は何も知らない
I don't know anything at all.
君はもう子供じゃないことも
Even that you're no longer a child,
慣れない他人の手の温もりは
and the unfamiliar warmth of someone else's hand
ただ本当に 本当に 本当に 本当のことなんだ
is just truly, truly, truly real.
やめない やめない
You won't stop, you won't stop,
君は何故やめない？
why won't you stop?
見つかれば殺されちゃうくせに
Even though you'll be killed if they find you.
雨上がりに 忌み子が二人
After the rain, two outcast children
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
were swallowed into the sunset and faded away.
日が暮れて夜が明けて
Day turned to night and night turned to dawn,
遊び疲れて捕まって
exhausted from playing, we were caught.
こんな世界 僕と君以外 みんな居なくなればいいのにな
In a world like this, if only everyone besides you and me would just disappear...
みんな居なくなればいいのにな
If only everyone would just disappear...
知らない 知らない 声が聞こえてさ
I heard unfamiliar, unknown voices,
僕と君以外の全人類
and all of humanity, except for you and me,
抗う間もなく 手を引かれてさ
without a moment to resist, had their hands pulled,
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
and were swallowed into the sunset and faded away.
知らない 知らない
I don't know, I don't know,
僕は何も知らない
I don't know anything at all.
これからのことも 君の名も
Neither what comes next, nor your name.
今は 今は これでいいんだと
For now, for now, that this is fine,
ただ本当に 本当に 本当に 本当に思うんだ
I just truly, truly, truly, truly believe.
知らない 知らない あの耳鳴りは
That unfamiliar, unknown ringing in my ears
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
was swallowed into the sunset and faded away.
風を置いて
Leaving the wind behind,
雨を抜けて
breaking through the rain,
咲き誇れ
bloom in full glory!
あぁ 夜風に揺られている
Ah, swaying in the night breeze,
折れないように怯えている
terrified of breaking.
ずっと雨に濡らされている
Constantly drenched by the rain,
またどうしたって凍えてしまったんだ
no matter what, I ended up freezing again.
誰か この声に応答して
Someone, please answer this voice,
痛がるばっかで 咲けないままのハートを
and this hurting heart that cannot bloom.
あぁ 今
Ah, right now,
見逃せないくらい
so brightly you can't miss it,
綺麗に咲かせたいんだ
I want to make it bloom beautifully!
光っていた未来が
If the shining future,
ずっと待っていた世界が
the world we've been waiting for all along,
きらめく音の中にあるなら
lies within these sparkling sounds,
最低で最悪な涙も
then even the lowest, worst tears,
痛がりで嫌いな声も
and this vulnerable voice I hate so much,
連れて行きたいんだ 全部
I want to take it all along!
不完全な毎日が
When our imperfect days
一瞬のカケラたちが
and fleeting fragments
重なってこんな歌を奏でたら
overlap to play a song like this,
それは
it will
言葉だけじゃ届かない距離を
surely leap across the distance words alone cannot reach
きっと飛び越えて 結ぶ
and connect us,
きっと輪を描いていく
surely drawing a circle around us!
さあ涙を拭いて
Come on, wipe your tears,
喉を鳴らして
clear your throat,
テンポを飛ばせ 上がってく
...pick up the tempo, rising higher
ほら 我が身 乗って 気取って 浮いて
Come on, get on board, put on airs, and float away!
ベロを回せ グルーヴを取らんぜ 伏せく
Roll your tongue and ride the groove
混んがらがって つまんないのも
Even getting tangled up and bored,
迷ったら踊れ センセーショナル
if you hesitate, just dance, it's sensational!
浮かまない脳に馴染まないで
Don't settle for a dull mind
声を枯らせ 泥だらけになっても生きていたい
Let your voice go hoarse; even if covered in mud, I want to live
今夜 あの空で合流して
Tonight, let's meet up in that sky
朝が満たすまで
until the morning fills the dawn,
それぞれの星を探そう
let's search for our own stars.
ねぇ 今 同じこと思っていたんだって
Hey, right now, we were thinking the exact same thing.
ほら 話さなくても分かり合えた
Look, we understood each other without even speaking.
あぁ あぁ こんな嬉しさを
Ah, ah, such boundless joy,
ずっと歌ってみたかった
I've always wanted to sing about this!
光っていた未来が ずっと待っていた世界が
The glowing future, the world that was always waiting,
煌めいて目の前にあるから
is sparkling right before our eyes, so...
瞬きの刹那まで
Until the blink of an eye,
このストーリーの最後まで
until the very end of this story,
輝く花でいたいな
I want to remain a blooming, radiant flower.
不完全な私達が 一瞬の欠片達が
Imperfect as we are, like fleeting fragments,
重なってこんな歌を奏でたんだ
we overlapped to create such a melody.
それは 夢見るだけじゃ叶わない想いを
Those feelings that won't come true just by dreaming,
ずっと 新しくしていく
we will constantly make brand new.
ずっと追いかけて行こう
Let's keep chasing after them forever!
風を裂いて
Tearing through the wind,
雨を抜けて
breaking through the rain,
咲き誇れ 満天の空へ
bloom proudly into the sky full of stars!
Ah...
ノンブレス・オブリージュ
作詞・作曲: ピノキオピー
[Non-Breath Oblige
Lyrics & Music: PinocchioP]
世界中のすべての局面に好かれるなんて気持ち悪いよ
Being liked by every single person in the world is just disgusting.
だけど一つになれない教室で 君と二人 手を繋いでいたいの
But in a classroom where we can never be one, I just want to hold hands with you.
数の暴力に白旗をあげて 悪感情を殺してハイチーズ
Raising the white flag to mob rule, killing off all ill feelings, say cheese.
ポストトゥルースの甘いディープキス エロく歪んでるラブアンドピース
A sweet deep kiss of post-truth, a lewdly twisted love and peace.
自己中の光線銃 乱射する 強者のナンセンス
Indiscriminately firing ray guns of selfishness, the sheer nonsense of the strong.
オートクチュールで作る 殺しのライセンス
A haute couture license to kill.
分断を生んじゃった椅子取りゲーム 無痛分娩で授かるベイブ
A game of musical chairs that birthed division; a baby delivered painlessly.
壮大な内輪ノリを歴史と呼ぶ
Calling a grand inside joke "history."
生きたいが死ねと言われ 死にたいが生きてと言われ
Wanting to live, yet told to die; wanting to die, yet told to live.
幸せ自慢はダメ? 不幸嘆いてもダメ?
Can't I brag about being happy? Can't I lament my misfortune either?
図々しい言葉を避け 明るい未来のため
Avoiding shameless words for the sake of a bright future...
さん はい
One, two!
「この世には息もできない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are so many people in this world who can't even breathe!"
さん はい
One, two!
「この世には息もできない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are so many people in this world who can't even breathe!"
あちらが立てば こちらが立たず
Pleasing one side means offending the other;
譲り 奪い 守り 行き違い
yielding, taking, protecting, passing each other by.
地雷原で立ち止まり 大人しく犬になるんだワン
Halting in a minefield, meekly becoming a dog, woof!
ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath,
オブリージュ
oblige.
I love you
息苦しい日々の水面下
Under the surface of these suffocating days,
ゆらゆらと煙る血の花
a swaying, smoldering flower of blood.
ぼくらは コンプレックス コンプレックス コンプレックス コンプレックス
We, complex, complex, complex, complex,
コンプレックスを武器に 争う
fight using our complexes as weapons.
それぞれの都合と自由のため
For each person's convenience and freedom,
息を止めることを 強制する
forcing each other to hold our breath.
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる
Suffocating, suffocating, suffocating, suffocating,
suffocating, suffocating, suffocating, suffocating,
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる
suffocating, suffocating, suffocating...
生き方が死ねと言われ 死にたいが生きてと言われ
Told our way of life should die; wanting to die, yet told to live.
正当防衛と言ってチェーンソーを振り回す
Wielding a chainsaw in the name of self-defense,
まともな人たちが怖いよ
the "normal" people are truly terrifying.
愛嬌爛漫 春爛漫
Charming and radiant, spring in full bloom;
日々だんだん 大事なものが消えていくよ
day by day, precious things keep disappearing.
さん はい
One, two!
「この世には愛も知らない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are so many people in this world who don't even know love!"
さん はい
One, two!
「この世には愛も知らない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are so many people in this world who don't even know love!"
共感 羨望 嫉妬 逆恨み
Empathy, envy, jealousy, resentment,
黒い涙がこぼれ落ち
black tears spill and fall,
醜い感情が噴き出し
ugly emotions gush out,
真っ白い鳥になるんだな
turning into pure white birds.
ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath,
オブリージュ
oblige.
I love you
深海魚と泳ぐ氷点下
Below freezing, swimming with deep-sea fish,
見上げているザラメの星
looking up at stars made of granulated sugar.
ぼくらは 直接 直接 直接 直接
We, directly, directly, directly, directly,
手を下さないままで
without ever getting our own hands dirty,
想像力を奪う 液晶越しに
through LCD screens that rob our imagination,
息の根を止めて 安心する
snuff out their breath and breathe a sigh of relief.
ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath,
オブリージュ
oblige.
I love you
それぞれの都合と自由のため
For each person's convenience and freedom,
息を止めることを 強制する
forcing each other to hold our breath.
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる
Choking, suffocating, choking, suffocating,
choking, suffocating, choking, suffocating,
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる
choking, suffocating, choking, suffocating.
息を止める 息を止める 息を止める 息を止める
Holding my breath, holding my breath, holding my breath,
holding my breath, holding my breath, holding my breath,
息が詰まる 息を止める 息が詰まる 息を止める
choking, holding my breath, choking, holding my breath,
choking, holding my breath, choking, holding my breath.
ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス・オブリージュ
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige.
I love you それぞれの好きを守るため
I love you, to protect what each of us loves,
君と防空壕で呼吸する
I breathe with you inside an air-raid shelter.
酸素が足りない...
Not enough oxygen...
酸素が足りない... 酸素が足りないんですけど...
Not enough oxygen... I'm running out of oxygen, but...
はい... ざ、続けてやらせていただきました。
Yes... I performed them back-to-back.
はい、いかがだったでしょうか？
So, how did you like it?
隙間の配信で話したんですけど、
I mentioned it during a previous stream,
あの、一部人間じゃない奴があるって言ってたのが、
that there were some inhuman tracks in the setlist,
この「ノンブレス・オブリージュ」と、
and that was this "Non-breath Oblige",
ま、先ほどね、ソロでやらせていただいた「六兆年と一夜物語」でした。
along with "Six Trillion Years and Overnight Story" that I performed solo earlier.
はい。
Phew.
純粋に、すごく心配だったんですけど、
Honestly, I was super worried about them,
なんとかね、なんていう... 良かったという... 今、すごい安心で今、震えております。
but somehow... how do I put it... I'm so relieved they went well that I'm literally trembling right now.
はい！というわけで、ここまでたくさん見ていただきましたが、
Yes! So, we've had so many performances up to this point,
みなさん、いかがですかー？
everyone, how are you enjoying it?
ゲストもね、めっちゃ来てもらって、AZKiちゃんと、
We had so many guests join us too, like AZKi-chan,
あと、ミオ先輩、フレア先輩、そして、わため先輩、ねね先輩も、ありがとうございます！
and Mio-senpai, Flare-senpai, as well as Watame-senpai and Nene-senpai, thank you so much!
あの、本当にみんなと歌ってみたい曲を、自分が好きな曲と、
Really, songs that I wanted to sing with everyone, songs I personally love,
「この人にこれを歌ってるとこを聞きたい」っていう気持ちで選んで、
and choosing with the feeling of "I really want to hear them sing this song,"
一緒にね、やらせていただきました。本当にありがとうございます！
we got to perform them together. Thank you all so much!
先輩たち、ありがとーーー！
Thank you so much, senpais!
ちょっと、一旦水飲んでいいか... 水を飲ませてくれ...
Let me just grab a drink of water... Please let me drink some water...
よいしょ。
All right.
はい。はい、ちょっと落ち着きました。
Okay. Yes, I've calmed down a bit now.
はい。ということで、まだまだ続くんでね、次の曲いきたいと思うんですけど、
Yes. So, the live is still going on, so I'd like to move on to the next song,
次の曲は、あの、昨日のオタクトークでもめっちゃリクエスト上がってて、でその前からずっとリクエスト上がってて、
and for this next song, there were so many requests for it during yesterday's otaku talk stream, and even way before that too,
いやこれ生誕ライブにやりたいなってことで、ずっと取っておいた曲です。
and thinking, "I really want to perform this for my birthday live," I've saved it all this time.
なんで、楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです。
So, I hope you all enjoy it.
それでは、次の曲聴いてください。
Now then, please listen to the next song:
「ray」
"ray."
お別れしたのはもっと 前の事だったような
It feels like saying goodbye happened so much longer ago.
悲しい光は封じ込めて 踵すり減らしたんだ
Locking away that sorrowful light, I wore down the heels of my shoes.
君といた時は見えた 今は見えなくなった
I could see it when I was with you, but now it has disappeared from sight:
透明な彗星をぼんやりと でもそれだけ探している
that invisible comet, vaguely, yet that is all I search for.
しょっちゅう唄を歌ったよ その時だけのメロディーを
I sang songs all the time, melodies that belonged only to those moments.
寂しくなんかなかったよ ちゃんと寂しくなれたから
I wasn't lonely at all, because I was able to properly feel lonely.
いつまで どこまでなんて 正常か 異常かなんて
"Until when?" or "How far?" "Is it normal, or abnormal?"
考える暇も無い程 歩くのは大変だ
Walking is tough enough that there's no time to even think about it.
楽しい方がずっといいよ ごまかして笑っていくよ
Having fun is so much better; I'll laugh it off as I go.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは 忘れたって消えやしない
It's all right; even if I forget that pain, it will never disappear.
理想で作った道を 現実が塗り替えていくよ
Reality paints over the path paved by ideals.
思い出はその軌跡の上で 輝きになって残っている
And along that trail, memories remain shining bright.
お別れしたのは何で 何のためだったんだろうな
Why did we part ways? What was it all for, I wonder?
悲しい光が僕の影を
A sorrowful light stretches my shadow...
A sad light casts my shadow...
前に長く伸ばしている
...stretching it out long before me.
時々熱が出るよ
Sometimes I get a fever,
時間がある時眠るよ
and I sleep whenever I have the time.
夢だと解るその中で
Inside the dream I know is just a dream,
君と会ってからまた行こう
I'll meet with you, and then move on again.
晴天とはほど遠い
Far from clear blue skies,
終わらない暗闇にも
even in this endless darkness,
星を思い浮かべたなら
if I picture the stars in my mind,
すぐ銀河の中だ
I'm instantly right inside the galaxy.
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I rarely cry anymore,
靴を新しくしても
even if I get brand-new shoes,
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
it's alright, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
...won't fade away even if I forget it.
伝えたかった事がきっとあったんだろうな
There must have been things I wanted to tell you.
恐らくありきたりなんだろうけど
They were probably quite ordinary, but still...
こんなにも
...so very much.
お別れした事は
The fact that we said goodbye...
出会った事と繋がっている
...is connected to the fact that we met.
あの透明な彗星は
That transparent comet,
透明だから無くならない
because it's transparent, will never be lost.
○×△ どれかなんて
Circle, cross, or triangle, whichever one it is,
皆と比べてどうかなんて
comparing myself to others and wondering how I measure up,
確かめる間も無い程
without even time to check,
生きるのは最高だ
being alive is truly the best!
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I rarely cry anymore,
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll laugh it off and keep going forward.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
It's alright, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
...won't fade away even if I forget it.
大丈夫だ この光の始まりには
It's alright, at the very beginning of this light...
君がいる
...you are there!
はい！ということで、rayでしたー！
All right! That was "ray"!
あー、どうだったでしょうか？
Ah, how did you like it?
めっちゃ、え、エモい、エモい...
It turned into a really, uh, emotional...
感じになりましたね。はい。
...emotional atmosphere, didn't it? Yes.
ちょっと一瞬水飲んでいいですか？
Can I drink some water for just a second?
水、水が...
Water, where's the water...
飲んでも飲んでも減らない水、いいだろう。風真いろは特注だぜ。
Water that never runs out no matter how much you drink, nice, right? Custom-made for Kazama Iroha!
よいしょ、ちょっと待って。
All right, give me a second.
よし、はい。
All right, okay!
というわけで、次のね、曲にいきたいと思うんですけど、
So, I'd like to move on to the next song, but...
まああの昨日の枠で、ちょっと匂わせをしたんですが、
well, I kind of dropped a hint on yesterday's stream,
え、本日ですね、あの視聴者参加型3D生ライブになっておりまして、
today is an interactive viewer-participation 3D live concert!
はい。今回はですね、皆さんに投票をしていただいて次に歌う曲決めたいと思います！
Yes! Today, I want you all to vote to decide the next song I'll sing!
なんじゃらほいって思うかもしれないんですけど、視聴者参加型曲決め合戦って言う事です。
You might wonder what that means, but it's an interactive viewer song-choice showdown!
それではテロップどうぞ！
Show the graphic, please!
ジャジャーン！
Ta-da!
えー、「ANIMA」か「ただ声一つ」。どっちか！
Um, "ANIMA" or "Tada Koe Hitotsu." Which one?
で、投票が少なかった方も、この後メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブで歌いますので、よろしくお願いします。
Whichever song gets fewer votes, I'll sing it afterwards in the member-exclusive encore stream, so stay tuned!
いや、どちらも名曲で迷いますよね。
They're both such great songs, it's hard to choose!
今スタッフの人と、どっちになるかねっていうのを賭けてます。
Right now, the staff and I are placing bets on which one will win.
あの、どっちに賭けてるとか言わないんで、さあみんなこれで次回の差し入れが豪華になるか裏で決まるからな！
I won't say which one I bet on, but everyone, backstage refreshments for next time depend on this!
はい。というわけで早速投票を開始していきたいと思います。大体時間は1分ぐらいですかね？
Yes! So let's start the voting right away. We'll have about one minute, right?
それでは、用意、スタート！
Ready... set... START!
ちょっと来た？
Are votes coming in?
今、来たかな？
Are they coming in now?
あ、来たござ！来た来た、来た来た来た来た来た！
Ah, it's here-goza! It's here, here it comes, here it comes!
はい、じゃあみんな、投票ボタン押してね！
All right, everyone, make sure to hit that vote button!
じゃあみんなが投票やってる間に、ゆっくりみんなのこと待つために帰るわ、メインステージ。
While you're all voting, I'll take my time heading back to the main stage to wait for you.
じゃ、移動ですよ、移動～
Okay, moving along, moving along~
はい、というわけで、みなさん
All right, so then, everyone...
投票した？できてる？
Did you vote? Are you done?
どっちかだよ！
Pick one of the two, okay?
両方は、両方はちょっとあれだからね！どっちか、どっちかい、どっちかでお願いします！
Both, voting for both would be a bit much! Just one, which one? Pick one, please!
そういえば今、なんだかんだこうやって歩かせてもらってますが、
By the way, as I'm walking across the stage like this,
実はね、なにげにね、
to tell the truth, casually,
ファーストミッション衣装がね、見せるのが、ゆっくり見せるのは、初めてだったりするんだっけ？
showing off this First Mission outfit... is this the first time I'm taking my time to show it?
そう、そうだ！ここで、ここでさ、宣伝しとこう。着服詐欺じゃないよ？
Right, exactly! Let me do a little promotion here. No, it's not a scam!
あの宣伝ね！このあとメン限でアフターライブがあるんですけど、
Just a promo! There's an after-live stream in membership right after this,
そのね、時に、もっとこのカッコいいところね、いっぱい見せますので！
and during that, I'll show off a lot more of all these cool details!
なんでぜひ良かったらメン限のアフターライブにもお越しくださ～い！っていう宣伝も入れつつ、
So if you'd like, please come join the membership after-live~! And with that promo plugged...
みんな入れた？入れた？
Did everyone vote? Did you vote?
いや、すごいなこれ花道。長くない？
Wow, this runway is incredible. Isn't it super long?
ながっ、長くない？
It's so long! Isn't it long?
これ、これ現地ライブでもやりたいな～。
I'd really love to do something like this at an in-person concert too~.
はい、もうだいぶカッコいい風真いろはさんをいっぱい見せているわけなんですが、
Yes, I've already been showing plenty of cool Kazama Iroha today,
いやでもどっちかな～これ！
but man, which one is it going to be?!
ANIMAはね、みんな、知っての通り、あの、カッコいい、カッコいいで、
ANIMA is, as you all know, really cool and intense,
ただ声一つはしっとり、しっとりなんでね、ちょっと好みは分かれると思いますが、
while Tada Koe Hitotsu is emotional and mellow, so preferences might be split, but...
はい、いやきっとね、どっちやってもみんなカッコいいって言ってくれるよね？
yeah, whichever one wins, everyone will still tell me I'm cool, right?
言ってくれるよね？
You will, right?
え、言って、言ってくれる？あ、言って、言ってくれ、あ、もうカメラは言ってくれるってことで！
Eh, will you tell me? Ah, you'll... the camera says you will!
はい、というわけでみんな、もう大丈夫かな？オッケー？
All right, is everyone all set now? Are we good?
じゃあそろそろ終わっちゃいますからね！
We're going to wrap up the poll in just a moment!
はい、早く早く！早く投票してね！
Hurry, hurry! Cast your votes quickly!
はい、はい。え？終わった？終わったのよね、スタッフさん？終わった？
Okay, okay. Huh? Is it done? It's over, right, staff-san? Is it over?
早かった、歩くの？
Did I walk too fast?
終わった？終わっ、終わっ、終わったかな？あ、
Finished? Did it... did it finish? Ah,
あ、なんか終わったらしい！
ah, looks like it's done!
今、賭けをしているスタッフとにらめっこしてます。
Right now, I'm having a staring contest with the staff who placed bets.
それでは、結果発表ターイム！
And now, it's time to announce the results!
トゥルルルルルルルルルルルルルル...
Trrrrrrrrr...
ダダン！
Ta-da!
アンケートの結果、ANIMAになったみたいでーーす！
According to the poll results, it looks like ANIMA won!
あ、これあの、賭けに勝った人の動きです。
Ah, this is the dance of someone who won their bet.
うーーい！早速いただきました！よっしゃあ！
Woohoo! Taking the win right away! Alright!
というわけで、あの賭けにも勝ち、みなさんにも選んでいただき、とてもありがたい限りですね。
And so, winning the bet and having you all choose it, I'm truly grateful.
あのただ声一つの方も、このあとメンバーシップ限定で歌いますので、そちらもお楽しみにー！
I'll also be singing Tada Koe Hitotsu in the members-only stream after this, so look forward to that too!
と、いうわけで、早速歌っていきましょうか。
And with that, shall we get right to singing?
それでは聴いてください。ANIMA。
Please listen: ANIMA.
魂の色は
What color is
何色ですか
the color of the soul?
もういっそ 折れたままで
“Might as well just stay broken”
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
I'm not strong enough to throw it away
強くないよ ほら
or to run away from it, look
もう一度 鼓動 高鳴る
Once again, my heartbeat quickens
何が正しいかなんて わからないけど
Even though I don't know what is right or wrong,
形のないものばかりが
only things without form
大切になって行く
keep becoming more precious to me.
飾らない言葉だけが
Only unadorned words
強く結ばれてる
are bound together strongly.
また躓いて 転がって
Stumbling and tumbling again,
それでも砕けない
yet still not shattering,
魂の色は
what color is
何色ですか
the color of the soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって
Just getting hurt, putting up a brave front,
それでも見つけたいよ
yet still I want to find it.
魂のカタチ
The shape of the soul,
確かめてるよ
I am confirming it.
深い地の底で一人
Alone deep beneath the earth,
扉と鍵を探す
searching for a door and a key.
おとぎ話は ほら
Fairy tales, you see,
泡の様に全部消えて
all vanish like bubbles,
葛藤 残像だけ
leaving only conflicts and afterimages
次の頁へ
to the next page.
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて
The spreading branches and leaves diverge,
それぞれの道を行く
each following their own path.
they go their separate ways.
寂しい思い出だけが
Only lonely memories
強く根を張ってる
take deep root.
まだ貫いて
Still piercing through,
失って それでも挫けない
losing, yet still refusing to be discouraged.
心はどこに
Where is the heart?
器はどこに
Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて
Just left behind,
抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
shedding away, yet I still want to tell you...
魂の日々を
...about the soul's days,
魂の意志を
about the soul's will,
ずっと
forever.
魂の色は
What color
何色ですか
is your soul?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
What color
何色ですか
is your soul?
透明な過去に
In a transparent past,
不透明な明日に
in an opaque tomorrow,
生きるあなたは
as you live on,
何色ですか
what color are you?
また躓いて
Stumbling again,
転がって それでも砕けない
falling, yet still unbreakable.
魂の色は
What color
何色ですか
is your soul?
ただ傷ついて
Just getting hurt,
強がって それでも見つけたいよ
putting up a brave front, yet I still want to find it.
魂のカタチ
The shape of the soul,
確かめてるよ
I'm confirming it,
ずっと
forever.
はい、ということで、
Yes! And with that,
ANIMAを歌わせていただきましたー！
that was my performance of "ANIMA"!
カロリー高い方だったなぁ。
Whew, that really burned a lot of calories.
ちょっと水、水ください。
Um, water... please give me some water.
カロリー高い方だった。
That was a high-calorie one.
危ない。
That was close.
あ、すいません。
Ah, sorry.
あの、ナチュラルにマイクを返すの忘れていました。
Um, I naturally forgot to hand back the mic.
やばい、音変になってなかったらいいな。すいません。
Oh dear, I hope the audio didn't turn out weird. Sorry!
ナチュラルに...
Naturally...
スタッフさんがすっごい手伸ばしてくれたのに、疲れすぎてここ硬直してた。
Even though the staff reached out so far, I was so tired I completely froze up right here.
はい。
Alright.
水うまい。
Water is delicious.
やっぱ水のおかげで生きていけてます。
After all, water is what keeps me alive.
はい、じゃちょっとこれ返して...
Okay, let me hand this back...
はい！それではですね、まあちょっと、まだまだ続くんですけど、
Alright! Well then, there's still plenty more to come, but...
ここいらで一旦、重大告知タイムをさせていただきたいと思います！
I'd like to take a moment here for an important announcement!
じゃまずはいっものからいくか！
Then let's start with the usual!
じゃあまずはこちら！
First up is this!
風真いろは、誕生日記念
Kazama Iroha Birthday Celebration
グッズ2026出ます！ドンドコドンドンドン！
2026 merchandise is here! *drumroll*
いやー、なんか良さそうなラインナップですねー！
Wow, looks like an amazing lineup!
はい、今回もとってもこだわったグッズばかりなんで、みなさん楽しみにしていてほしいです！
Yes, these are all items crafted with great care again, so I hope you all look forward to them!
では、1つずつ商品見ていきましょう！
Now, let's take a look at the items one by one!
まずは、こちら！
First up is this!
タペストリーが出ます！
A tapestry is coming out!
タペストリー、実は個人グッズで出すの超久しぶりなんですよね。
Actually, it's been super long since I last released a tapestry as personal merch.
イラストはもちぷよ先生描き下ろしで、雨上がりの青空の下で、
The illustration is newly drawn by Mochipuyo-sensei, under the blue sky after the rain,
もう本当にね、このステージみたいな感じで、あのライブをしている風真いろはのイメージで描いていただきました！
really like this stage, picturing Kazama Iroha performing live! That's the image they drew!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
いや、めっちゃいいよね。飾ってね。
Isn't it wonderful? Be sure to put it up!
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
フード付きタオル！
A hooded towel!
はい、タペストリーと同じイラストのフード付きタオルです。
Yes, it's a hooded towel featuring the same illustration as the tapestry.
フード部分はぽこべぇの顔になっており、取り外しが可能となっております。
The hood part features Pokobee's face and is detachable.
いやなんか、こないだね、あの、ホロックスのライブあったじゃん？
You know, the other day we had the holoX live concert, right?
でなんか、ダンスの先生に教えてもらったんだけど、
And my dance teacher told me...
なんか風真隊、異様にタオル購入率が良かったらしいな、お前たち！
Apparently the Kazama-tai had an insanely high towel purchase rate, you guys!
首にいっぱい巻いてくれててえらいぞ！
You wrapped so many around your necks, good job!
...出すんで、あのー
...so, um—
これで自認ポコ兵ごっこができるようになります！
With this, you can pretend to be Pokobee!
自認ポコ兵ごっこをしたい方、
For those who want to roleplay as Pokobee,
ま、取り外してそのまま飾りたい方もね、どうぞ！
or just detach the hood and display it, go right ahead!
はい、そしてお次はこちら！
Alright, and next up is this!
ペットボトルホルダー！
A plastic bottle holder!
あの、これは風真いろはさんが欲しいの作っ作ってくれました。
Um, they made this because Kazama Iroha wanted one!
あのイラストは、さめあんこ先生に描いていただきました。可愛いでしょ！
The illustration was drawn by Sameanko-sensei. Isn't it cute?
この真ん中の穴に、あのギュってペットボトルのところを入れてね、
You push the neck of a plastic bottle tightly through the center hole,
あのー、使うやつです。はい。
and use it like that. Yup.
めっちゃおしゃれです。よかったら使ってください。
It's super stylish, so please use it if you'd like.
カバンとかね、つけて持ち運べるんでね。
You can attach it to a bag and carry it around.
はい！
Yes!
そしてラストはこちら！
And lastly, this one!
はい！
Yes!
実は地味になかった、セーラー服ver.の風真いろはのぬいぐるみ、なんとボイス付きです！
Something we surprisingly didn't have: a Sailor Uniform ver. Kazama Iroha plushie, with voice lines!
こちらもさめあんこ先生に原案考えていただきました。
Sameanko-sensei helped come up with the concept design for this one too.
レインポンチョを着た、声が出るぬいぐるみです。
It's a talking plushie wearing a rain poncho.
ま、あのお手手握り締めると音が出るらしいぞ。
Apparently, it plays audio when you squeeze its little hand.
今のところはな。はい。
At least that's the plan. Yup.
外出時にカバンなどにつけることもできます。
You can also clip it to your bag when going out.
で、ボイスなんですけど、なんか天気に関するもの撮ったんですよ。
And regarding the voice lines, I recorded weather-themed ones!
どんな感じかはまだね、流石に言えないけど。
I can't spoil what they're like just yet,
だけど、あのおみくじ感覚で聞いて、
but you can listen to them like drawing a fortune,
あのその天気にならなかったからといって風真いろはを責めないでください。
so please don't blame Kazama Iroha if the weather turns out differently!
自己責任で、もうにぎにぎしてください。
Squeeze it at your own risk!
買ってからのお楽しみです。
Look forward to it after you buy it!
いっぱいありましたが、フルセット見ていきましょう！
There were many items, but let's take a look at the full set!
こちら！
Here it is!
今回のグッズはですね、生誕のイメージに合わせてフェス風をテーマに作ってみました！
For this birthday merch, I designed them with a festival theme to match the live!
実用性たっぷりだし、これからの季節にぴったりなんで、よかったらよろしくお願いします！
They're super practical and perfect for the upcoming season, so please check them out!
そしてフルセット購入特典は、えーこちら！
And the bonus for purchasing the full set is... this!
数量限定版あ、あります！
There is a limited quantity version!
風真いろはの直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージ入りチケット風カード！
A ticket-style card with Kazama Iroha's handwritten autograph and foil-stamped message!
ちょっとおしゃれな感じですね。
It's got a pretty stylish vibe.
そして通常版には箔押し複製サインとメッセージ入りチケット風カードがついてきます。
And the standard version includes a ticket-style card with a foil-stamped replica autograph and message.
えー、さらにどちらにも、えー、ま、ボイスがついてきますね。はい。
Plus, both versions come with a bonus voice track. Yup!
「君と雨宿り」というなんかタイトルのボイスがついてくるんですけど、ま、ぶっちゃけあの、
It comes with a voice track titled "Taking Shelter from the Rain with You," but honestly...
気になったら聞いてください。
if you're interested, please give it a listen.
ボイス、滅多に出さないからね。
I rarely ever release voice packs, after all.
はい、ということで、ま、シチュエーションボイスですね。雨宿り系
So yes, it's a situation voice track. A sheltering-from-the-rain theme,
だった気が...なんかちぎりながら録った気がします！
I think... I feel like I recorded it while tearing myself apart!
そしてグッズは21時カートオープンです！
And the merch cart opens at 21:00!
すみません、あの生配信につきちょっと時間が押しそうなんですけど、
Sorry, since this is a live stream, time is running a bit over, but...
あの、「ゆっくり買ってね」とは言えず、
I can't really tell you to "take your time buying," so...
頑張ってください！
good luck!
なんて言ったらいいかわからない、ごめん！
I don't know what else to say, sorry!
そしてあの21時からホロメンあの多分配信控えてると思うんですけど、あの何も気にしなくていいんです、スタートしてくださいね。
And other Holomem probably have streams scheduled starting at 21:00, but please don't mind me at all and go ahead and start!
はい！
Alright!
そして、まだまだあります！
And there's still more!
まだまだ！それがこちら！
Still more! Take a look at this!
はい、新曲！イエーイ！
Yes, a new song! Yay!
風真いろはさん、新曲が出ます。
Kazama Iroha is releasing a new song!
タイトルは「風向きエントロピー」
The title is "Kazamuki Entropy"!
作詞作曲は、「いろはすてっぷ！」でもおなじみ、40mPさんにしていただきました！
Written and composed by 40mP, who also worked on "Iroha Step!"!
はい、配信後にこちらMVが公開されます。
Yes, the music video will be released right after this stream.
多分こっそり今マネちゃんがプレミア公開に切り替えてくれているはず。
My manager is probably secretly setting it to premiere right now.
楽曲は0時リリースになっております！
The song will be released digitally at midnight!
はい！
Yes!
そしてあのちょっと気づいた人もいるかもしれないんですけど、
And some of you might have already noticed,
ジャケットの文字は風真いろはさんが自分で書きました。はい。
but Kazama Iroha wrote the jacket cover lettering herself. Yup.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
ということで、
So,
もう終わっちゃうんですけど、
the live is already coming to an end,
なんかすごいトレンド2位とかに入ってるっていう連絡を受けました！
but I just got word that we're trending at #2!
くそっ！
Dang it!
「あと残り頑張ってくれ」と言いたいけど、
I want to say "keep pushing for the rest!",
でもみんな本当にいっぱいポストしてくれてありがとうね！
but seriously, thank you all so much for posting a ton!
よし、準備できた？
Alright, are you ready?
音等の準備ができてそうなので、
Looks like the audio and stage setup are ready,
早速新曲歌っていきたいと思います！
so I want to sing the new song right away!
がしかし、今回はちょっと特別なものを用意してきました！
But wait, I've prepared something special for today!
ゴンドラ来い！
Come here, gondola!
おー！リハーサルで見たけどやっぱいいなこれ！
Ooh! I saw it during rehearsal, but this is so cool!
ほい！というわけで、
Yup! So,
みんなポコ兵がいなくて寂しかったでしょ？
you guys were lonely without Pokobee, right?
今年はゴンドラになりました！
This year, it became a gondola!
はい！というわけで、早速やっていくんですが、
Yes! So let's get right to it...
ドア、オープン！
Door, open!
イェイ！ほっ！
Yay! Up we go!
もっちょむにー
Mocchomunii~
というわけで、早速歌っていきたいと思います。
And with that, I'd like to jump right into singing.
それでは聴いてください。風真いろは新オリジナル曲「風向きエントロピー」
Please listen to Kazama Iroha's new original song: "Kazamuki Entropy".
風向きエントロピー
作詞・作曲・編曲：40mP
[Kazamuki Entropy
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: 40mP]
ねぇ いつからそこにあったの？
Hey, since when was it there?
あまりにも近くて気づかなかったよ
It was so close, I didn't even notice.
ずっと 私が生まれた日から
All along, since the day I was born,
そばにいてくれたのにね
even though you were always by my side.
曖昧で 複雑で 予測不可能で
Vague, complex, and unpredictable,
気まぐれに変わっていく空の模様
the pattern of the sky constantly changes on a whim.
想像していたように
I can't smile as well...
上手く笑えない
...as I had imagined,
だけどそれ以上に
but even more than that,
世界は優しくて
the world is kind.
いつか風が生まれた
The place where the wind was once born,
足跡が始まる場所
where footprints first began.
あの頃に戻って 帰って
Even if I turned back to those days, returned,
駆け出したとしても ここに来るんだろう
and started running, I'd still end up here.
この景色も この声も
This scenery, this voice,
私を彩るすべて
everything that colors who I am.
方向なんてまだわからないけど
I still don't know the direction yet,
ただ風の吹くままに
but I'll just follow wherever the wind blows.
ねえ いつから気づいてたの？
Hey, since when did you know?
まるで私のこと全部お見通しで
It's like you can see right through all of me.
苦し紛れにごまかした嘘も 君にはバレていたのかな
Did you see through the desperate lies I told to cover things up?
平凡で退屈で欠伸ばかりで
Ordinary, boring, doing nothing but yawning,
変哲のないありふれてる時間
in these unremarkable, everyday moments.
想像しているだけじゃ 何も変わらない
Nothing will change just by imagining it,
だけどそれ以上に
but even more than that,
予測してた以上に
even more than I predicted,
ほら 新しい風が吹いてきて
look, a new wind has started to blow,
不器用な自分がやけに愛しく思えたんだ
and I found my clumsy self surprisingly endearing.
はあ...
Haa...
いつか風が止んで
The place where the wind once ceased,
足跡が途切れた場所
where footprints came to a halt.
落とし物探して 拾って
Because I searched for, picked up, and found...
見つけ出せたから ここにいるんだろう
...what was lost, that must be why I'm here.
そっと 髪が靡く
Gently, my hair flutters in the breeze.
いつか風が夢見た
The place the wind once dreamed of,
青空と交わる場所
where it intersects with the blue sky.
回り道選んで 迷って
Even if I took detours, got lost,
躓いたとしても そこへ行くんだろう
and stumbled, I'd still head there.
この景色も この声も
This scenery, this voice,
私を彩るすべて
everything that colors who I am.
等身大の手で握りしめて
Holding on tight with my own two hands,
想像以上にもっと自由な速度で
at a speed far freer than I ever imagined.
方向なんてまだわからないけど
I still don't know the direction yet,
ただ風の吹くままに
but I'll just follow wherever the wind blows.
はい！というわけで、ありがとうございましたー！
Alright! And with that, thank you so much!
よいしょ。みんな、すっかり忘れてると思うけど、
There we go. Everyone, you've probably completely forgotten, but...
今日これから、記念撮影しまーす！
we're going to take a commemorative photo now!
そう、お土産があるって言ったっしょ？
That's right, I mentioned there'd be a souvenir, right?
これこれ。え、ちょっと待って。マジで自撮り棒...これリハーサルでめっちゃ練習したのに！
This is it. Wait, hold on. Seriously, this selfie stick... Even though I practiced so much with it during rehearsal!
自撮り棒下手...あ、いい感じいい感じ。
I'm so bad with selfie sticks... Ah, that's looking good, looking good.
カシャ。
*Click*
うし、行けてそう行けてそう。オッケー！
All right, looks like it worked, looks like it worked. Okay!
はい。というわけで、みなさーん。
Yes. So, everyone...
今日お土産ありって言いましたね。
I told you there would be a souvenir today.
そうなんです！今日撮った、今この風真がね、自撮り棒で撮った写真が、
That's right! The photo that was taken just now by me with the selfie stick...
コンビニで、なんとプリントアウトできます！
can actually be printed out at convenience stores!
すごーい！
Amazing!
はい。こちらはですね、対象店舗ファミリーマートさん、ローソンさん、ミニストップさんで、
Yes. You can get it at participating FamilyMart, Lawson, and Ministop stores...
本日21時からネットで事前購入ができます。
with online pre-purchases starting tonight at 9:00 PM.
お値段がですね、税込み300円とのことで、
The price is 300 yen including tax...
印刷できるようになるのは、明日の6月19日20時からになっております。
and printing will become available tomorrow, June 19th, starting at 8:00 PM.
写真にはですね、複製手書きメッセージ、あの、この後書きますんで。
And on the photo, I'll be writing a printed handwritten message afterwards.
はい。どんな写真が撮れているか、ちょっと写真下手くそでも怒んないでね？
Yes. As for what kind of photo came out, please don't get mad even if I'm bad at taking photos, okay?
あの、内容は買ってから確認してください！
Please check out the contents after you buy it!
いや、すごいよね。ちょっといち早く皆さんの元に、
It's pretty amazing, right? We wanted to get something into your hands as soon as possible...
あの、なんか手元に残るライブのね、お土産が用意できればということで、
like a tangible live concert souvenir to keep...
今回やらせていただきました。お土産あります！
so that's why we did this. We've got souvenirs for you!
ちょっと皆さん各自で回収...
So everyone, please go pick yours up...
そしてそれだけが申し訳ないんですが お見合いがありますんで
And I'm sorry about this, but it's a bit of a random draw,
ぜひ気になったら コンビニでプリントしてみてください！
so if you're interested, please try printing them at a convenience store!
そしてコンビニプリント購入できるのは 7月21日17時59分までです！
And the convenience store prints will be available until July 21st at 5:59 PM!
概要欄に 写真こういうの リンク多分今マネちゃんがやってくれてると思いますので
In the description box... I think Mane-chan is putting up the link for these photos right now,
よろしくお願いします！
so please check it out!
そしてこの後はですね MVの公開と メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブありますので
And coming up next, we have the MV release and the membership-exclusive encore live,
そちらも絶対聞いてくださいねー！
so be sure to tune into that as well!
それでは皆さん またお会いしましょう！
Well then, everyone, see you again soon!
最高の誕生日でした！
This was the absolute best birthday!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!